Okonkwo, Thomas

Phone: +1 (405) 402 8242 Location: Houston, Texas thomokc@gmail.com

Portfolio: http://thomasokonkwo.com

Social Media:







Prairie View A&M University

M.Sc Computer Science 3.90/4.00

University of Lagos, Akoka, Nigeria.

B.Sc Electrical and Electronic Engineering 3.08/4.00

SKILLS

Streaming: Kafka, Spark Streaming BigData platform: MapR

Backend: Java (Spring Boot), REST, Python, Flask, Scala, SQL, Apache Beam

Infrastructure: Kubernetes, Docker, Jenkins, GCP

Miscellaneous: Algorithms, Big Data, Machine Learning, Hadoop Others: Hadoop, Apache Drill, Apache Spark, Neo4j, hive, HBase

OBJECTIVE

I am a motivated computer science student from Prairie View A&M University with a keen interest in Software Development and Machine Learning. A solution-oriented team player with a recognized aptitude for innovative thinking. I am enthusiastic, responsible, and hardworking. Having worked on different projects, it has helped me to adapt to changes quickly and made me a mature team worker. I can work well both in a team environment and as well as using my own initiative.

SCHOOL PROJECT

Cerber Malware Detection— *Research and machine learning Engineer*

FALL 2022 - Computer Network Security

AUG. 2021 - PRESENT

SEPT. 2013 - JAN. 2018

- Worked on research for detecting Cerber Ransomware Created a machine learning model for detecting if a packet capture(pcap) file is a Cerber Ransomware or not.
- Cerber pcap files were used to train the model using TF-IDF methodology, where the weight of any input parameter from the pcap file will serve as terms used to measure the weight and frequency of occurrence.

Centralised IOT-Based Monitoring for Cell Tower Sites— Backend Engineer

FALL 2022 - Software Engineering

- I worked in a team of 5 in the design of the centralised IOT-Based monitoring for cell tower sites. I handled the design of the database using postgres and python flask for the backend. The aim of the project was to remotely monitor cell tower sites in different locations.
- I created endpoints for the CRUD operation with python flask and also an endpoint for report generation to track which cell tower fails for easy monitoring with graphical representation of the cell towers on each cell site.

Course Advisor Management System — Backend Engineer

FALL 2021 - Database Management

• Worked in a team of 4 to design the course advisor management system where I worked on the database design and REST API. I used Java and Spring Framework for the API, and SQL to query the mySql database. The Course advisor Management system is an application with a user interface to add, edit or remove classes for each semester.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Twitter Inc. — Engineering intern

MAY 2022 - AUG 2022

- Built software applications in service of machine Learning using Apache beam: Worked with the Machine Learning Data Framework team to build data pre-processing tools for machine learning.
- Wrote beam jobs for different computation using Google Cloud Storage, using machine learning data framework
- Built libraries using Apache beam and using google dataflow and Notebooks to inspect behaviours while streaming
- Anchored the intern leadership series event with one of Twitter's executives A global event where interns meet with Twitter's executives and share their experiences with Interns.

RESEARCH / VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Prairie View A&M University- Research/Graduate Assistant

OCT 2021- Present

- Working on research for accurately and precisely locating the mobile genetic elements (mobile DNA) in the genome to generate phylogenetic trees. The machine learning classification and clustering is used to make the phylogenetic trees.
- Working on research in the civil engineering department building a machine learning model for predicting soil moisture content in Geotechnical engineering, and building different statistical models on data obtained from different sites in Texas and analysing them.

Oklahoma State University- Research Assistant (Summer Volunteer)

MAY 2021- AUG 2021

- Developing a Machine Learning model for early prediction of sepsis using clinical data.
- Improving the efficiency of an already existing Machine Learning model to increase the accuracy of the model from 93% to 97%.

Personal Research in Machine Learning

NOV. 2017- SEPT. 2018

• Analysed stock data (from yahoo data) and built machine learning models to predict estimated output and profits using regression analysis.

EDUCATION

Software Engineer









•	•	Publish	ed mach	ine learn	ing article	s on med	ium to tea	ch newbie	es on creat	ting mach	ne learnin	g models fi	om scratch.